Christian Brown

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Details

Greenaway House, Forest Road GU22 8LU, Woking United Kingdom 07584508986 robrowno@icloud.com

Links

Linkedin

Github

Skills

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Python

Agile

Languages

English

Italian

French

Hobbies

I'm a keen motorsports enthusiast, currently racing in the 2022 MINI Rally Challenge. My navigator and I won the DST leconsfield stages in May 2022, which was my second ever rally.

I enjoy going to the gym and going on walks with my dog to keep active as much as possible.

I'm a Bass Player of over 7 years and I love listening and playing along to classic rock music.

Profile

A Full-Stack Software Development Student looking for my first role as a Software Developer. I am currently studying and working towards my diploma with the Code Institute, on one of the only university-accredited courses in Europe.

I have 5 year's work experience in high-quality Automotive companies such as Mercedes-Benz Brooklands, McLaren Automotive Ltd and The Global Motoring Hub Ltd in roles ranging from service technician to paint shop technician and acting production team leader.

I'm an avid learner looking to develop in an exciting and fast-paced industry. I'll bring great communication skills with me along with a can-do attitude and a growth-mindset.

Employment History

Bodyshop Technician, The Global Motoring, Feltham

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Utilised my skills as a paint-prepper to deliver cars to the painters.
- I worked hard to ensure quality was always up to par, and in my time here, I have also learned to polish and detail cars after the paint process.
- I have really enjoyed working and learning from other more experienced technicians.

Paint Shop Production Team Member, McLaren Automotive Ltd, Woking

OCTOBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Paint Shop Technician at The McLaren Production Centre. Variety of tasks to
 perform at the beginning of the paint shop production line, including lining
 and masking of cars, jig/skid building, goods-in parts quality checks and hand
 prepping and auditing panels before being primed.
- I also covered for the Team Leader, which involves creating load plans and processing data for the shift.
- Towards the end of my time at McLaren, I was the Acting Team Leader for MPC
 Paint Shop Load Team working as the Team Leader as well as working on
 process on the shop floor to ensure a smooth transition between the previous
 and current Team Leader.
- During this time I developed new management skills and helped in defect tracking, load planning and networking between departments (Logistics, Body Assembly and various Engineering+SQA teams). I reported to the Shift Manager to discuss any concerns during production and achieve production targets.

Hospitality Team Member, Absolute Taste, Woking

JANUARY 2018 - OCTOBER 2018

Restaurant, Cafe & Hospitality employee within the MTC in Woking.

- Varied hospitality work across the McLaren Technology Centre within the Restaurant, Cafe
 /Juice-Bar and Hospitality on the upper floors, respectively.
- I attribute learning most of my networking and customer-based skills to this role, where I interacted with all levels of McLaren Automotive, Applied & Racing staff.
- Some essential machinery maintenance was required. Cleaning and parts maintenance/replacement of coffee and vending machines.
- A typical shift involved routine food and drink service, completing daily cleaning and service preparation tasks and taking stock of requirements within the restaurant and juice bar.

Service Technician Work Experience, Mercedes-Benz Brooklands, Weybridge

AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2018

- I was taught the basics of car mechanics and how to perform A and B services on Mercedes-Benz passenger cars along with other maintenance and repair work such as bleeding brakes and changing brake pads.
- I was able to assist in MOT's and help the Technicians by bringing parts for jobs each day.

Education

Diploma in Full-Stack Software Development, Code Institute, Dublin

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

- Full Stack Software Development Course with the Code Institute.
 Consisting of a 5 portfolio/coursework structured learning programme, I am working my way through to achieve my diploma.
- My 5 projects include the following:
 - Project 1: HTML5 & CSS3
 - Project 2: HTML5, CSS3 & Javascript (Vanilla)
 - Project 3: Python
 - Project 4: Full Stack (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Python, Bootstrap, Agile, Flask, Jquery)
 - Project 5: E-commerce/Advanced Front-End/Data Analytics project (TBC)

High School Diploma, ITS College Asia, Hong Kong

JANUARY 2016 - JULY 2017

Online Learning from Hong-Kong based school ITS Education Asia. Studying Maths, Physics and Chemistry whilst I was based in Japan.

GCSE, The British School in Tokyo

SEPTEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2015

GCSE subjects and grades:

- English: A*
- Maths: A
- Science: A
- Geography: A**
- History: A
- French: A**
- Physical Education: C

Secondary School, St George's British International School, Rome

JANUARY 2010 - JULY 2014

Secondary School Year's 7-10:

• Completed GCSE Italian Grade: A*

Awards

McLaren Q3 Manufacturing Award 2021

Awarded for spotting defects in stock of a production-ready part that prevented issues/stoppages down the production line, saving the company time and money in rework and stock retake from suppliers.

Associated with my time at McLaren Automotive Ltd.